Dutch Painting Photograph Collection
Yale University Arts Library
- R (Box 40)
  - Individual Artists R., 1195 (Box 40)
    - Rembrandt van Rijn, 1606-1669., 962 (Box 40)
      - Paintings., 805
        - Amsterdam., 67 (Box 44)
          - Rijksmuseum., 63
            - The Syndics of the Cloth Guild., 8 (Box 44)
            - The Holy Family at Night., 5 (Box 45)
        - Baltimore., 3 (Box 45)
        - Basel., 3 (Box 45)
        - Berlin., 50 (Box 45)
          - Miscellaneous subjects., 4 (Box 45)
          - Portraits and self-portraits., 23 (Box 45)
          - Religious themes., 16 (Box 45)
          - St. John the Baptist Preaching., 7 (Box 45)
        - Boston., 19 (Box 45)
        - Brunswick., 7 (Box 46)
        - Cambridge., 3 (Box 46)
        - Cassel., 44 (Box 46)
        - Chicago., 9 (Box 46)
        - Cleveland., 7 (Box 46)
        - Cologne., 6 (Box 46)
        - Detroit., 13 (Box 47)
        - Dresden., 21 (Box 47)
        - Dublin., 3 (Box 47)
        - Edinburgh., 5 (Box 47)
        - Florence., 5 (Box 47)
        - Frankfurt., 8 (Box 47)
        - Glasgow., 8 (Box 47)
        - The Hague., 34 (Box 48)
        - Hamburg., 4 (Box 48)
        - Leningrad/St. Petersburg., 23 (Box 48)
        - London., 79
          - Miscellaneous collections., 15 (Box 48)
          - The Wallace Collection., 10 (Box 49)
          - National Gallery., 54 (Box 49)
        - Los Angeles., 9 (Box 50)
        - Minneapolis., 3 (Box 50)
        - Munich., 29 (Box 50)
        - New York., 95 (Box 50)
          - Miscellaneous collections., 25 (Box 50)
          - Frick Collection., 9 (Box 50)
          - Metropolitan Museum of Art., 61 (Box 51)
        - Paris., 28 (Box 51)
        - Paris., 27 (Box 52)
        - Rotterdam., 12 (Box 52)
        - San Francisco., 6 (Box 52)
        - Stockholm., 19 (Box 53)
        - Toledo., 2 (Box 53)
        - Vienna., 20 (Box 53)
        - Washington, D.C., 32 (Box 53)
        - Washington, D.C., 31 (Box 54)
        - Zurich., 4 (Box 54)
      - School of Rembrandt., 10 (Box 54)
    - Renesse, Constantijn A., 1626-1680., 2 (Box 54)
    - Ruysch, Rachel, 1664/5-1750., 6 (Box 54)
    - Ruysdael, Jacob van, 1625/6-1682., 130 (Box 55)
      - Drawings., 3 (Box 55)
      - Paintings., 127 (Box 55)
        - Miscellaneous locations., 29 (Box 55)
        - Places A-Z., 39 (Box 55)
        - Amsterdam., 9 (Box 55)
        - Boston., 4 (Box 56)
        - Cincinnati., 3 (Box 56)
        - Cleveland., 4 (Box 56)
        - Detroit., 4 (Box 56)
        - Dresden., 5 (Box 56)
        - London., 10 (Box 56)
        - New York., 6 (Box 56)
        - Paris., 6 (Box 56)
        - Rotterdam., 4 (Box 56)
        - Washington, D.C., 4 (Box 56)
    - Ruysdael, Salomon van, 1600-1670., 30 (Box 56)
    - Ruysdael, Salomon van, 1600-1670., 20 (Box 57)
- S (Box 57)
  - Miscellaneous Artists S., 45 (Box 57)
    - Schalcken, Godfried, 1643-1706., 3 (Box 57)
    - Schelfhout, Andreas, 1787-1870., 5 (Box 57)
    - Schotel, Johannes, XIX Century., 1 (Box 57)
    - Schouman, Aert, 1710-1792., 2 (Box 57)
    - Schrieck, Otto-Marseus van, 1613-1673., 1 (Box 57)
    - Schuer, Theodor van, 1628-1707., 1 (Box 57)
    - Schuhmacher, Wim, 1894-., 1 (Box 57)
    - Schumacher, Emil, 1912-., 1 (Box 57)
    - Schwartze, Johan Georg, 1814/5-1874., 1 (Box 57)
    - Sjollema, J. S., 1901-., 1 (Box 57)
    - Slingelandt, 1640-1691., 1 (Box 57)
    - Sluyters, Jan, 1881-1957., 2 (Box 57)
    - Smits, Jakob, 1855-1928., 2 (Box 57)
    - Sorgh, Hendrik Martens, 1611-1670., 3 (Box 57)
    - Soutman, Pieter Claesz, 1580-1657., 1 (Box 57)
    - Steenwyck, Hendrik van, the Elder, 1550-1603., 1 (Box 57)
    - Steenwyck, Hendrik van, the Younger, c.1580-c.1649., 1 (Box 57)
    - Stevaerts, Anthonie Palamedesz, 1600-1673., 2 (Box 57)
    - Stevens, Pieter, XVII Century., 1 (Box 57)
    - Stomer, Matthias, c.1600-1650., 3
    - Streeck, Juriaen van, 1632-1687., 1 (Box 57)
    - Stomer, Matthias, c.1600-c.1650., 1 (Box 57)
    - Stork, Jan, active 1660-1684., 1 (Box 57)
    - Strij, Jacob van, 1756-1815., 1 (Box 57)
    - Sturm, Fernando, 1537-., 2 (Box 57)
    - Swanenburgh, Willem, 1581/2-1612., 1 (Box 57)
    - Swanvelt, Herman van, 1600-1655., 1 (Box 57)
    - Swart, Jan van Groningen, 1500-1553., 3 (Box 57)
  - Individual Artists S., 201
    - Saenredam, Pieter, 1592-1667., 36 (Box 57)
    - Saftleven, Herman, 1609-1685., 9 (Box 58)
    - Schooten, Floris Gerritsz van, active 1655., 3 (Box 58)
    - Scorel, Jan van, 1495-1562., 23 (Box 58)
    - Seghers, Hercules P., 1590-c.1640., 16 (Box 58)
    - Somer, Paul van, 1576-1621(?)., 3 (Box 58)
    - Steen, Jan, 1626-1679., 103 (Box 59)
      - Miscellaneous locations., 50 (Box 59)
      - Amsterdam., 10 (Box 59)
      - Berlin., 7 (Box 59)
      - The Hague., 8 (Box 60)
      - London., 17 (Box 60)
      - New York., 6 (Box 60)
      - Paris., 5 (Box 60)
    - Sweerts, Michiel, 1615/20-1656., 8 (Box 60)
- T (Box 60)
  - Miscellaneous Artists T., 13 (Box 60)
    - Tempel, Abraham van den, c.1662-1673., 1 (Box 60)
    - Teniers, David, the Younger, 1610-1690., 1 (Box 60)
    - Ter Borch, Gesina, 1633-1690., 1 (Box 60)
    - Ter Borch, Moses, 1645-1667., 2 (Box 60)
    - Terwester, Mattheus, 1670-1757., 1 (Box 60)
    - Thorn-Prikker, Jan, 1869-1932., 2 (Box 60)
    - Thulden, Theodore van, 1607-1676., 2 (Box 60)
    - Tillemans, Peter, 1684-1734., 2 (Box 60)
    - Troostwijk, Wouter Joannes van, 1782-1810., 1 (Box 60)
  - Individual Artists T., 150 (Box 60)
    - Ter Borch, Gerard, the Elder, 1584-1662., 14 (Box 60)
    - Ter Borch, Gerard, the Younger, 1617-1681., 60 (Box 61)
      Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings (may have both the Elder and the Younger.)
    - Ter Borch, Gerard, the Younger, 1617-1681., 24 (Box 62)
    - Terbrugghen, Hendrik, 1588-1629., 26 (Box 62)
    - Tonny, Kristian, 1907-., 3 (Box 62)
    - Toorop, Jan, 1858-1928., 18 (Box 62)
    - Troost, Cornelis, 1697-1750., 5 (Box 62)
- U (Box 63)
  - Miscellaneous Artists U., 5 (Box 63)
    - Utrecht, Jacob van, active 1506-1524., 1 (Box 63)
    - Uyl, Jan, 1595-1639., 1 (Box 63)
    - Uytenbroek, Moysesz van, 1590-1648., 3 (Box 63)
- V (Box 63)
  - Miscellaneous Artists V., 24 (Box 63)
    - Vellert, Dirck, active 1511-1544., 1 (Box 63)
    - Verelst, Simon Pieterz, 1644-1721., 2 (Box 63)
    - Verendael, Nicolaes van, 1640-1691., 1 (Box 63)
    - Verheijen, Jan Hendrik, 1778-1846., 1 (Box 63)
    - Verkade, Jan, [Dom Willibrod], 1868-1946., 1 (Box 63)
    - Vermeulen, Jan, XVII Century., 1 (Box 63)
    - Vermeyen, Jan Cornelis, 1500-1599., 3 (Box 63)
    - Verster, Floris, 1861-1927., 1 (Box 63)
    - Verswijver, Pol, XX Century., 1 (Box 63)
    - Verwer, Abraham de, c.1600-1650., 1 (Box 63)
    - Vijbrief, Jan, 1868-1895., 2 (Box 63)
    - Vinkeles, Johannes, 1741-1816., 1 (Box 63)
    - Vliet, Hendrik van, 1611-1675., 1 (Box 63)
    - Vois, Arie de, c.1632-1680., 1 (Box 63)
    - Voogd, Hendrik, 1766-1839., 1 (Box 63)
    - Voort, Cornelis van der, c.1576-1624., 1 (Box 63)
    - Vos, Peter, 1935-., 1 (Box 63)
    - Vrel, Jacob, active c.1654-1662., 1 (Box 63)
    - Vries, A. de, 1590-1650., 1 (Box 63)
    - Vries, Hans Vredeman de, 1527-1604., 1 (Box 63)
  - Individual Artists V., 704 (Box 63)
    - Van Gogh, Vincent, 1853-1890., 441 (Box 63)
      - Miscellany., 3 (Box 63)
      - Drawings., 47 (Box 63)
      - Paintings., 391 (Box 64)
        Includes a fat folder of miscellaneous clippings.
        - Locations not marked., 50 (Box 64)
        - Private Collections., 66 (Box 64)
        - Public Collections., 275 (Box 65)
          - Collections A-Z., 43 (Box 65)
          - Amsterdam., 69 (Box 66)
          - Boston., 11 (Box 66)
          - Chicago., 12 (Box 66)
          - Cleveland., 4 (Box 67)
          - Edinburgh., 5 (Box 67)
          - Essen., 4 (Box 67)
          - London., 15 (Box 67)
          - Moscow., 5 (Box 67)
          - New Haven., 5 (Box 67)
          - New York., 24 (Box 67)
          - Otterlo., 48 (Box 68)
          - Paris., 18 (Box 68)
          - Washington, D.C., 12 (Box 68)
    - Vanvittelli, Gaspare, 1653-1736. (Box 69)
      See: Wittel, Gasper van.
    - Velde, Adriaen van der, 1630-1672., 18 (Box 69)
    - Velde, Bram van, 1895-1981., 4 (Box 69)
    - Velde, Essaias van de, 1591-1630., 13 (Box 69)
    - Velde, Jan van de, 1620-1660., 3 (Box 69)
    - Velde, Willem van der, the Elder, 1610-1693., 10 (Box 69)
    - Velde, Willem van der, the Younger, 1633-1707., 28 (Box 69)
    - Venne, Adriaen Pietersz van de, 1598-1662., 7 (Box 69)
    - Vermeer, Johannes, 1632-1675., 127 (Box 70)
      - Suspected forgeries., 1 (Box 70)
        See also: Hans van Meegeren, forger.
      - Miscellaneous locations., 24 (Box 70)
      - Amsterdam., 19 (Box 70)
      - Berlin., 4 (Box 70)
      - Boston., 6 (Box 70)
      - Dresden., 8 (Box 70)
      - Frankfurt., 4 (Box 71)
      - The Hague., 9 (Box 71)
      - London., 11 (Box 71)
      - New York., 13 (Box 71)
      - Vienna., 12 (Box 71)
      - Washington, D.C., 16 (Box 71)
    - Verspronck, Johannes Cornelisz, 1597-1662., 14 (Box 72)
    - Victors, Jan, 1620-1676., 4 (Box 72)
      Artist's name also spelled "Victoors."
    - Vinckboons, David, 1576-1632., 12 (Box 72)
      Artist's name also spelled "Vinckeboons."
    - Visscher, Cornelis, c.1629-1658., 5 (Box 72)
    - Vlieger, Simon de, 1600-1653., 7 (Box 72)
    - Vroom, Cornelis Hendricksz, c.1591-1661., 5 (Box 72)
    - Vroom, Hendrick Cornelisz, c.1562/3-1640., 6 (Box 72)
- W, X, Y & Z (Box 73)
  - Miscellaneous Artists W, X, Y & Z, 31 (Box 73)
    Includes a folder of miscellanous clippings.
    - Walscapelle, Jacob van, 1667-1716., 1 (Box 73)
    - Waterloo, Anthonie, 1609/10-1690., 3 (Box 73)
    - Wiegers, Jan, 1893-1959., 1 (Box 73)
    - Wieringen, C. C. van, c.1580-1643., 1 (Box 73)
    - Weissenbruch, Johann Hendrik, 1824-1903., 1 (Box 73)
    - Westerbaen, Jan, 1600-1686., 1 (Box 73)
    - Wet, Jacob Willemsz de, c.1610-c.1671., 2 (Box 73)
    - Wiegman, Matthieu, 1886-., 1 (Box 73)
    - Wieringen, Cornelius Claesz van, c.1580-1643., 1 (Box 73)
    - Wijck, Thomas, 1616-1677., 1 (Box 73)
    - Wijnants, Jan, c.1625-1684., 1 (Box 73)
    - Wijnen, Domenicus van, 1661-., 2 (Box 73)
      Artist's name also spelled "Wynen."
    - Willaerts, Adam, 1577-1664., 2 (Box 73)
    - Willink, Albert Carel, 1900-1983., 1 (Box 73)
    - Wissing, Willem, 1656-1687., 4 (Box 73)
    - Witsen, Willem, 1860-1923., 1 (Box 73)
    - Wollheim, Gert, 1894-1974., 1 (Box 73)
    - Wolvens, Henri-Victor, 1896-1977., 2 (Box 73)
    - Wouters, Rik, 1882-1916., 2 (Box 73)
    - Woutersz, Johannes, c.1599-c.1663., 1 (Box 73)
    - Wuchters, Abraham, 1610-1682., 2 (Box 73)
    - Zanden, Ed. van, 1903-., 1 (Box 73)
  - Individual Artists W, X, Y & Z., 123 (Box 73)
    - Wagemaker, Jaap, 1906-., 5 (Box 73)
    - Weenix, Jan, 1640-1719., 10 (Box 73)
    - Weenix, Jan Baptiste, 1621-1663., 13 (Box 73)
    - Werff, Adriaen van der, 1659-1722., 5 (Box 73)
    - Wit, Jacob de, 1695-1754., 7 (Box 73)
    - Witte, Emanuel de, c.1617-1692., 20 (Box 74)
    - Wittel, Gasper van, 1653-1736., 7 (Box 74)
    - Wouwerman, Philips, 1619-1668., 40 (Box 74)
    - Wttewael, Joachim, 1566-1638., 11 (Box 74)
    - Wijnants, Jan, 1630/34-1684., 5 (Box 74)